Witness the incredible true story.
NYAD is a drama, history film directed by Elizabeth Chai Vasarhelyi.
Athlete Diana Nyad sets out at 60 to achieve a nearly impossible lifelong dream: to
swim from Cuba to Florida across more than 100 miles of open ocean.
Diana Nyad, played by Annette Bening.
Bonnie Stoll, played by Jodie Foster.
John Bartlett, played by Rhys Ifans.
Nico, played by Ethan Jones Romero.
Luke Tipple, played by Luke Cosgrove.
Angel Yanigahara, played by Jeena Yi.
Nyad is a 2023 American biographical sports drama film about swimmer Diana Nyad's
multiple attempts in the early 2010s to swim the Straits of Florida.
It is directed by Elizabeth Chai Vasarhelyi and Jimmy Chin (in their feature narrative film
directorial debut) and written by Julia Cox, based on Nyad's 2015 memoir Find a Way.
It stars Annette Bening as Nyad, with Jodie Foster and Rhys Ifans.
Nyad had its world premiere at the 50th Telluride
Film Festival on September 1, 2023.
Following its premiere at the 2023 Toronto International Film Festival, it was released in
select theaters on October 20, 2023, then streamed on Netflix on November 3.
Nyad received positive reviews from critics, with particular praise for the performances of Bening and Foster who both received nominations for Best Actress and
Supporting Actress, respectively, at the 96th Academy Awards, 29th Critics' Choice Awards, 81st Golden Globe Awards, and the 30th Screen Actors Guild Awards.
The film explores themes of midlife crisis, affectation, biography,
based on true story, based on memoir or autobiography.
The tone is uplifting and emotional.